Greg: Hi! I’m Greg.
Welcome to Oxford.
I’m visiting the Old Bank Hotel.
It’s an unusual hotel in the centre of the city.
The Old Bank is in the High Street, in the centre of Oxford.
Today it’s a luxury hotel, but these buildings –
from number ninety-two to number ninety-four –
have a very interesting history.
In the sixteenth century, they were part of Christ Church College.
In the eighteenth century, they were different shops.
And we know that in 1808 the buildings were one business –
a bank.
There was a bank here for almost two hundred years,
but today it’s a famous Oxford hotel.
Would you like to go in and look?
Let’s go.
The Old Bank Hotel has a beautiful reception
and a fantastic restaurant.
There are forty-two bedrooms
and they’re all very comfortable.
They have great views of Oxford’s famous colleges.
This room has a large bed, two chairs, a table, a television, and a cupboard.
It has a beautiful marble bathroom, too.
But there are other rooms that visitors to the hotel don’t usually see.
These secret rooms are here in the cellar, under the hotel.
These are the old bank vaults.
When the hotel was a bank, all the money was here.
The rooms were small and the doors weren’t easy to open!
They were very, very strong,
and on each one, there was a large lock.
Today, these old vaults are storerooms.
The hotel keeps its wine collection in here, so it’s very, very safe!
Ninety-two to ninety-four High Street is a part of Oxford’s history.
And today, if you want to visit Oxford, the Old Bank is a fantastic place to see!